google released a new programming
language and we should probably ignore
it anonymous
nicolas inidan welcome to a new video c
plus plus has been around since 1985 and
to this day it still remains as the most
popular programming language when
building performance critical
applications which means software that
has to run fast
in 2015 the size of google's code base
was of 86 terabytes consisting of two
billion lines of code is spread across
nine
million files and a lot of that code is
written on c plus plus as you would
expect google has run into some problems
with c plus plus but improving c plus
plus the way google wants to improve it
is not an easy thing google wants to
improve c plus plus but the c plus plus
committee which is a group of people
from nvidia intel bloomberg oracle among
others prefers to focus on backwards
compatibility which means they don't
want to change the language so much that
all code will stop working because many
companies depend on c plus plus they
rather keep the language stable and
backwards compatible rather than
constantly evolving it because google
already has millions and millions of
lines of c plus plus code they cannot
just switch programming languages and
rewrite everything in rust for example
that will be crazy they need something
that is interoperable with c plus plus
and this is why they created carbon
carbon is as fast as c plus plus and it
has bi-directional interoperability with
c plus plus carbon code is able to call
c plus plus code and vice versa this is
huge because this means that they are
able to write new code using carbon but
they can still reuse old c plus plus
code carbon wants to do for c plus plus
what typescript did for javascript or
what kotlin did for java the syntax
difference between c plus plus code and
carbon code is not that big which means
c plus plus developers will have an easy
time when writing new carbon code and
calling carbon code from a c plus plus
file is trivial as well all we have to
do is write the function in carbon and
then import it in a c plus plus file and
we are good to go so why should we
ignore carbon as it says on carbon's
homepage if you can use any other
established programming language like go
swift kotlin or rust you should ignore
carbon carbon is for organizations that
have a lot of c plus plus code or use
many third party c plus plus libraries
carbon is fixing a very special problem
that not many companies have carbon is
also experimental it is years away and
even though it doesn't say in the
project homepage carbon is a google
product which means that as we know it
can be killed at any second let me know
in the comments what do you think about
carbon do you see yourself or your
company using carbon or do you think
google is going to kill it very very
soon thank you for watching as always
and don't forget if you want to learn to
code and you want to do it for free then
please click the link below and i will
see you there you will find lots of free
courses to teach you to code from
javascript to python react go redux
among many other things thank you as
always for your support i will see you
on the next video stay free eat kimchi
be happy see you next time bye